domestika.com 2017-09-03

# Privacy Policy | Domestika

## General

Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have developed this Privacy Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate and disclose and make use of personal information. The following outlines our privacy policy.

Domestika LLC. (“Domestika”) is an online platform where creative professionals can showcase their work and discover the creative work of others and where creative professionals can learn from each other through online classes. **Domestika is hosted exclusively in the United States** and is operated from the Domestika offices in San Francisco, California. Domestika may be accessed directly on the web at [www.domestika.org](http://www.domestika.org/) (together with all linked pages, the “Site”).

By accessing any part of the Site, **you are agreeing to the terms** and conditions described below (this “Privacy Policy”) and to the Terms of Use (the “Terms of Use”). If you do not agree to any of these terms, you should not use the Site. This Privacy Policy applies to all users, including both users who are simply viewing content available via the Service and users who have registered as members of Domestika.

The **text in the boxes** provides a brief explanation of the Privacy Policy and is not legally binding.

The **English version** of this agreement will be the version used when interpreting or construing this agreement.

You cannot use our Services unless you agree to our Terms and to our Privacy Policy, so please read both carefully.

## A Note to Users Outside of the United States

The **Service is hosted in the United States** and is intended for and directed to users in the United States. If you are accessing the Service from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Service, which is governed by United States law, this Privacy Policy, and our Terms of Use, you are **transferring** your personal information to the United States and you expressly consent to that transfer.

If you do not want your personal data to be processed in the USA, please, do not use the Site.

## Information collected by Domestika

**We only collect personal information that is relevant** to the purpose of our Site. This information allows us to provide you with a customized and efficient experience. We collect the following types of information from our users:

  1. ### Personal Information

**We receive and store any information you enter** on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features.

In order for you to use Domestika Services **you must complete a registration form**. As part of this registration form, we will ask you for **personally identifiable information**. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you. This includes, but is not limited to, your email address, your name, and your birthday, but does not include your credit card number of billing information. Braintree processes all of the transactions on Domestika, and the information you provide to Braintree is subject to its privacy policy1. We do not receive any of the credit card information you provide to PayPal.

To allow you to express yourself beyond just the information collected during registration, **we enable you to provide additional information in the user profile section** , such as a **bio** , your website address, your areas of interest, and your career preferences (location, type of job, etc.). In addition, you may choose to include photos of yourself in your profile.

Except for your birthday, e-mail address and phone, **all the information you decide to share with us will be published** under your profile. If you do not want that information to be published, do not fill in the relevant spaces of your profile or delete de information you have already submitted1.

We recommend that you **guard your sensitive information** and we encourage members to think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their profile pages. You can review and revise your profile information at any time.

In order to send you e-mail from Domestika, **we need your e-mail address**. To provide you with additional services, we may also request your name, geographical coordinates, and telephone number. We may give some or all of this information to the teachers for classes that you sign up for so that they can coordinate their classes. We will not give your name, email, or other personal information to unaffiliated third parties except with your consent or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

  2. ### Other Information

We use your **IP address** to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Site, and to analyze traffic patterns on the Site. We use **__**cookies, ** _web beacons_** and similar technology to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit. We may also use _web beacons_ and similar technology in emails that we send to you in order to track whether the emails have been opened. In addition, our web servers track information about the visits to the Site. For example, we compile statistics that show the daily number of visitors to the Site, the daily requests we receive for particular files on the Service, and what geographical areas those requests come from. These aggregated statistics are used internally to better provide services to the public and may also be provided to others.

  3. ### Third Party Websites

We may receive your personal data when you access or log-in to a third party website, e.g., Facebook, from our Site. This may include the text and/or images of your personal data available from the third party website.

We collect your registration and user profile data. Our servers also collect log information used to make the website faster and better. Also, to remember you, our system will give you a _cookie_. It's safe.

## Use and disclosure of your personal information

We may use and disclose your Personal Information only as follows:

  1. **To promote use of our Services**. For example, if you use any of our Services, and we think you might benefit from using another service we offer, we may send you an email telling you about it.
  2. **To send you System Alert Messages**. For example, we may let you know about temporary or permanent changes to our Services, like planned outages, new features, version updates, releases, abuse warnings, and changes to our Privacy Policy or Terms of Use.
  3. **To enforce compliance with our Terms of Use and applicable law**. This may include developing tools and algorithms that help us prevent violations.
  4. **To provide customer support**.
  5. **To protect the rights and safety of our users and third parties, as well as our own.**
  6. **To meet legal requirements** like complying with court orders and valid subpoenas.
  7. **To provide information to representatives and advisors** , like attorneys and accountants, to help us comply with legal, accounting, or security requirements.
  8. **To prosecute and defend a court, arbitration, or similar proceeding.**
  9. **To support and improve the Services we offer**. This includes adding new features to our current Services.
  10. **To communicate with you about your account for informational** , not promotional, reasons.
  11. **To transfer your information in the case of a sale, merger, consolidation, or acquisition**. In the event that we are acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right to transfer or assign the information we have collected from users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used.
  12. **To send you informational and promotional content that you may choose (or "opt in") to receive**. You can stop receiving our promotional emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in every email.
  13. **To third party service providers**. Except as otherwise stated in this policy, we do not generally sell, trade, share, or rent the personal data collected from our Site to other entities. However, we may share your personal data with third party service providers to provide services to us that enable us to make the Site and Services available to you. You expressly consent to the sharing of your personal data with our contractors and other service providers for the sole purpose of providing services to you. Access to your personal data by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function for us.
  14. In addition, **we may provide your personal information** to employees, consultants or other business or persons **for the purpose of processing such information on our behalf**. In such circumstances, we require that these parties agree to protect the confidentiality of such information and to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We collect information to make Domestika website useful for you. We do not sell your information to anyone. However, we will show publicly available information to other users and may release other information to authorities where required by law.

## Public Information and Third Parties

  1. ### Bio, forums, comments and online classes

We have public forums on our Site. Any information you include in your bio, in a comment on the forums, or under a project, may be read, collected, and used by anyone. Also, your profile pages and any online classrooms you participate in are typically publicly available. You should exercise caution before disclosing your personal information via these or any other public venues.

If your personal information appears on our forums and you’d like it to be removed, contact us by sending an email to [privacyofficer@domestika.org](mailto:privacyofficer@domestika.org). If we’re not able to remove your information, we’ll let you know why.

  2. ### Social Media Widgets

Our Site includes social media features, like the Pinterest button. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you’re visiting on our Site, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

  3. ### Links to Third-Party Sites

Our Site includes links to other websites, whose privacy practices may be different from Domestika’s. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

Third parties may collect your personal data on the Site. Please, read those third parties privacy policies.

## Third Party Tracking

Third parties, including linked sites and applications (e.g., Facebook and YouTube), customer support services and data analytics services, may collect information about you in connection with your use of the Site (e.g., usage information). Such third parties may use tracking technologies in connection with the Site and Services, which may include the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services. In some cases, third party tracking tools may only collect non-personal information about your use on the Site. However, in other cases, such third parties may collect personal data about you as they engage in these activities (e.g., customer support services may obtain your name and email address in conjunction with their support activities).

Currently, we do not monitor or take any action with respect to web browser signals or other mechanisms for the expression of choice regarding collection of information about an individual over time and across third-party web sites or online services (e.g., Web browser “do not track” signals).

Third parties may track the use you do of our Site.

## Feedback

If you provide feedback on the Site to us, we may use such feedback for any purpose, provided we will not associate such feedback with your personal data. Domestika will collect any information contained in such communication and will treat the personal data in such communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We will treat the personal data you give to us through feedback in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Children’s Privacy

You must be at least 13 years old to register to use the Site. Accordingly, we do not collect any personal information from children.

Please register only when you reach 18 years old, or ask your parents' permission if you are between 14 and 18 years old.

## Your California Privacy Rights

A business subject to California Civil Code section 1798.83 is required to disclose to its California customers, upon request, the identity of any third parties to whom the business has disclosed personal information within the previous calendar year, along with the type of personal information disclosed, for the third parties' direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to:

Domestika Privacy Officer  
610 22nd St.  
Suite 315  
San Francisco, CA 94107  
Email:[ privacyofficer@domestika.org](mailto:privacyofficer@domestika.org)

Please note that under California law, businesses are only required to respond to a customer request once during any calendar year.

If you are a California resident you can ask us for what we have been doing with your data in the last year.

## Accuracy of Data, Transparency, and Choice

We do our best to keep your data accurate and up to date, to the extent that you provide us with the information we need to do that. If your data changes (like a new email address), then you’re responsible for notifying us of those changes.

We only store data about you for as long as it’s reasonably required to fulfill the purposes that gave us the right to access it in the first place.

We’ll give you access to any personal information about you that we hold within 30 days of any request for that information you make by emailing [privacyofficer@domestika.org](mailto:privacyofficer@domestika.org). Unless it’s prohibited by law, we’ll remove any personal information about you from our servers at your request.

Privacy policy may change.

## Security of Your Personal Data

Domestika is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Despite these measures, you should know that we cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with personal data and mistakes may happen.

Your account is protected, but sometimes bad things can happen.

## Notice of Breach of Security

Nobody is safe from hackers. If a security breach causes an unauthorized intrusion into our system that materially affects you, then Domestika will notify you as soon as possible and later report the action we took in response.

If something bad happens we will notify you.

## Changes and Notification of Changes

We may, at our sole discretion, modify this Privacy Policy at any time. By accessing the Site at any time after such modifications, you are agreeing to such modifications.

In the event that we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and/or other places we deem appropriate, so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we ever intend to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify users by posting a notice on our website for 30 days.

Privacy policy may change.

## Contact Information

Domestika welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at [privacyofficer@domestika.org](mailto:privacyofficer@domestika.org) or contact us at the following address or phone number:

Domestika Privacy Officer  
610 22nd St.  
Suite 315  
San Francisco, CA 94107

Also, if you believe that we have not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [privacyofficer@domestika.org](mailto:privacyofficer@domestika.org). We will do our best to address your concerns. If you feel that your complaint has been addressed incompletely, we invite you to let us know for further investigation.

You can contact us if you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy.

## Effective date of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy was last modified as of February, 20, 2014.
